It's time to implement the red lines for the main activity. We
can do one part together so that you get the hang of it.
We begin by styling the list item Forecast Layout. The red line specifies
that the image should be 32 dp by 32 dp. We could hard
code the image view to be 32 by 32 dp, but it's actually
the same as leaving it as wrapped content for height and width. To
know what the icon size would be if we wrap content, we open
up the MDPI version of the icon and we do verify that it
is 32 pixels by 32 pixels. Whether we hard code it
or just add wrap content, visually, the imagine will still look
the same, but in the future it will be more flexible
if we just specify wrap content in case the image size changes.
Next we style the text. On ice cream sandwich and above,
Roboto is the default font for text views. It is created
specifically to satisfy the requirements of UI and to optimize for
high density screens. The red line indicates that the font family is
Roboto sans serif condensed, so we add that to the
code. On the topic of font sizes, having too many font
sizes in your app can confuse your user about the visual
hierarchy of your app, as to what's important and what's not
important. The Android design guide recommends these four type sizes
for consistency with a platform and for user experience. In our
app, we stick to the standard type sizes. And that's an
intentional part of the design, such as the large temperature values.
Hence, when the red line say that the date text
should be 22sp for font size, we could specify Android
text size to be 22sp, but the text appearance large
attribute already maps to that value. Note that the font
sizes are specified in S-P, not dips. S-P stands for
scaled pixels, so you can scale with the device font
size. In our app, we specify text appearance large and
text appearance small, which will give up 22spand 14sp respectively.
The default font color is black, so we don't need to specify
the android text color attribute on our text views. Let's look at the
spacing for the elements within the list item now. We have three children.
The first one is 60 dp wide, with the image centered inside of
it. So we can add a frame layout around the image view
and set the gravity to be center on the image, that way the
image centers itself within the parent. For the other two columns, we shouldn't
hard code such high dp values. Because otherwise the layout won't scale across
other devices. Instead, we can use linear layout weights, the weight of
seven here, and the weight of five. We just tried different values
until we got approximately equal to these values. The trick in doing
red lines is that you want to match the visual specs, but
you also want to be flexible in the code, so that it
adapts to different screen sizes. And this is what the code looks
like for the list_items_forecast layout. We
have a horizontal linear layout, containing
the frame layout with the image view. Then we have a vertical
linear layout with weight seven. And then we have another vertical layout
with weight five. We can check the link below for the full
code file. This is what is looks like when you're done. These
items looks polished, but we haven't gotten to the today item yet.